"有尾巴的这位先森才是家里的老大"
"The head of the family is the one with the tail."
天呀 我要看这部
God, I want to see this.
没啥问题吧 路易斯?
Finding everything okay, louis?
喔 恩 没什么问题
Oh, uh, yep.
多谢关心 科雷 我就随便看看
Thanks, corey. Just browsing.
呃 在动物喜剧区吗?
In the critter capers section?
哦
Oh.
我看成经典喜剧了啦
I thought it said "Criterion capers."
像那个法国探长的默剧
Like silent french police dramas.
"糊涂大侦探"
inspector.
哦 我一直在找这部电影呢
oh, here's the movie I was looking for.
"精灵之嗝"（这短语在法语里是小精灵的意思）
"La choffey."
是"精灵之歌"
"La chouffe."
这地精蠢呆了 你真有眼光
Gnome's folly. It's a great choice.
看吧 这就是为什么
See, this is why
你是我们最受欢迎的顾客之一 路易斯
you're one of our favorite customers, louis.
你 总是能发现好电影
You get film.
很多来这儿的人
Most of the other people who come in here,
只是想找梅尔·吉布森的最新电影
they just want the latest Mel Gibson movie
或是些车啊 追来追去的电影
or something with cars fighting.
但你不是
But not you.
你跟我们一样有品位
You're one of us.
我也这么觉得
I really am.
噢 好吧 你还欠了两美元的《潜艇风暴》滞纳金
Oh, okay, you have a $2 late fee on "Das boot."
但是 你懂得 你可是和咱志趣相投的影迷啊
But, uh, since you're a fellow cinephile,
那我就帮你
I'm just gonna go ahead
把这笔账"一笔勾销"了吧
And das boot that right off your account.
我懂你的梗
I understand that reference.
对了 你借的其他片子周二就到期 记得还哦
Uh, and your other rentals are due back tuesday.
其他片子?
Other rentals?
上周你家里人来这儿了
Somebody from your family came in last week
还租了一堆电影
and rented a bunch of movies.
什么? 谁?
What? Who?
我们店里不允许我们透露顾客的身份
Our store policy says we can't reveal our customers' identities
或者他们账户的其他信息
or any specifics on the account,
但我跟你说 他们的品位烂到不行
But I can tell you they have terrible taste.
要是我说了算 我不用他们还了
If it were up to me, they'd be due back never.
但不是我说了算
But it's not.
那 周二记得还啊
So, it's tuesday.
* Fresh off the boat
* I'm gettin' mine
everywhere I go *
* If you don't know, homey,
now you know *
* Fresh off the boat
* Homey, you don't know
where I come from *
* But I know where I'm goin'
初来乍到
第2季 第22集
* I'm fresh off the boat
埃迪 赶紧起床啊! 要去上学啦!
Eddie, up now! School!
埃迪是哪位?
Who's eddie?
我是多尔夫
I'm dorf.
"雷纳德 盯紧球啊"
"Leonard, keep your eye on the ball."
我不知道你在演谁 但我没时间跟你开玩笑
I don't know who that is, but I don't have time for jokes.
别再装病号了 赶紧穿好衣服啊
Stop playing invalids and get dressed.
好吧 到底是谁?
Okay, who was it?
是谁用了我的会员卡去租电影?
Who used my card to rent movies?
告诉我是谁就行了
Just tell me who it was.
我不会生气的
I won't be mad.
拜托
come on.
我知道是你们之中的一个家伙 拿了我的卡 去了录像店
I know one of you took my card, went to the video store,
让我在科雷面前出丑
embarrassed me in front of Corey.
路易斯 没人懂你在说什么玩意儿
Louis, nobody knows what you're talking about.
就让孩子们赶紧把早餐吃完吧
Let the boys focus on their breakfast.
干瞪眼比赛开始
Staring contest.
我不造啊 现在就比太早了啊
I didn't know. It's too early to compete.
晚了 我已经开始瞪你了
Too late. I'm staring at you!
埃迪 别再分散埃文注意力了
Eddie, stop distracting Evan.
他今天有个拼写测试 他得吃点东西
He has a spelling test. He needs to eat.
你可以一边吃一边瞪眼 对吧 埃文?
You can still eat, right, Evan?
我从没想过要这样
I never wanted this.
我先去外面等你们吧
I'll wait outside.
游戏结束了
Game over.
赶紧走
Now move.
我们打了个平手!
We tied!
好啦 快点 我们得出发了
Okay, come on. We got to go.
动作麻利点 好不
Let's go. Come on, please.
妈 你得在这上面签个字
Mom. I need you to sign this.
我不会再给你签什么
I'm not gonna sign another doctor's note
让你吃两份午餐的医生证明了
granting you permission to eat two lunches.
这是我的历史户外课的同意书啦
It's my permission slip for my history-class field trip.
户外课只不过是那些老师的带薪休假啦
Field trips are just paid vacations for teachers.
让他们带着我们的孩子在博物馆里乱转
I don't pay taxes so they can walk around a museum
然后告诉他们这幅罐头的画是多么的好看
telling our children
这我可不买账
that a painting of a soup can is beautiful.
虾米? 可是...
What?! But...
你们班去上户外课的时候
When your class goes on the field trip,
你就待图书馆学点中文啊
you can just do clc in the library.
就这样打住 行了
End of discussion. Okay.
你从来都不让我做任何事
You never let me do anything.
路易斯 我要跟蜜儿去商场办点儿事
Louis, I'm going with Honey to the mall to run some errands.
可能我就在那里吃份椒盐卷饼或是个甜甜圈了
Maybe I'll eat a pretzel or a doughnut.
知道了 等我把咖啡喝完
Okay! Just finishing my coffee,
我就像平时一样去上班啦
and then I'm off to work like normal.
就在我找到那些录像带之后
Just as soon as I find those tapes.
* Creepin' up on ya, creepin', creepin' up on ya *
* Don't try to put me down, I don't feel pain and sorrow *
* The sun will come out! * Yeah tomorrow, tomorrow
* I bet your bottom dollar that tomorrow, there'll be sun *
* Showin' gratitude, my attitude is kind of rude *
* I walk with a frown while I puff my cigar *
* Creepin' up on ya, creepin', creepin' up on ya *
什么鬼?
What the hell?
怎么那么多"奶奶"
So many nipples.
啊! 你抬它的时候别抓它脖子啊 路易斯
Ah! Don't lift him by the neck, louis.
抓蝶骨就好了
Lift him by the sphenoid.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
做的不错
对了 马文 实际上 我这次过来
Uh, marvin, I actually just came over
是想让你给我一些建议
to ask your advice about something.
啊 好了 真美啊
Uh, okay. What a beauty.
你知道吗 我打死它的时候 它正在喝水呢
You know, I got him when he was drinking water.
砰 这就是为什么它舌头是露出来的
Pow. That's why his tongue's out.
嗯 你刚刚说什么?
anyway, what were you saying?
哦 嗯 蜜儿有没有...
Oh, um, does Honey ever...
看过别的男人?
look at other men?
怎么这么问?
Why?
你他妈的听说什么了?
What the hell did you hear?
没听说什么 呃 只是...
Nothing. Uh, it's just...
我在杰西卡那半边床的底下 找到了一些录影带
I found some tapes under jessica's side of the bed.
都是些半裸男人的录像带
Shirtless-men tapes.
半裸男人的录影带?
Shirtless-men tapes?
都是动作片
Action movies.
史泰龙 施瓦辛格 尚格云顿
Stallone, Schwarzenegger, Van Damme.
哦 啊哈哈
Oh. Uh-huh.
所以你就担心自己没有满足
And you're worried that you're not giving jessica
杰西卡对动作片里的那种男性阳刚之气的渴望
the macho action-movie energy she clearly craves.
和你说 现在听到有人把这感觉说出来
You know, now that I hear it out loud,
还真的有点儿想多了啊
It does sound kind of crazy.
不 你没有想多
No, it doesn't.
你是应该为此担心
You should be worried.
- 什么? - 可能她是因为不想伤害你的感情
- What? - She probably kept it a secret from you
才瞒着你不说的
because she didn't want to hurt your feelings,
可是你完全不应该觉得自己被伤害了
which you shouldn't even have in the first place.
也许你是对的 马文
Maybe you're right, marvin.
今晚 我要和她坐下来 好好谈谈
Tonight, I'm going to sit her down and really talk it out.
谈?
Talk?
你就是因为这样 才会遇到这种问题的
That's what got you into this mess.
你看他们都是动作英雄 不是嘴炮英雄啊
They're action heroes, not talking heroes.
你要想解决问题 就得用实际行动
You want to solve the problem, you got to act.
你以为我是和那头鹿喝了个茶
You think I took that stag to tea
然后心血来潮就把它的脑袋挂在墙上的吗?
dnd floated the idea of mounting his head on my wall?
不 我就是直接开了一枪
No. I just did it.
砰!
Pow!
你想让杰西卡不要再看那些片子吗?
You want to stop jessica from watching those tapes?
那你就要证明给她看 你就是那样的男人
You got to show her you can be that kind of a man.
砰
Pow.
砰! 砰!
Pow! Pow!
我跟你说了 那就是他!
I'm telling you, it was him!
为什么史蒂芬·泰勒(美国音乐人)会出现在
奥兰多的尖端印象店(专营潮品的店)里?
Why would Steven Tyler be at the sharper image in Orlando?
因为他要买一个防雾的剃须镜 蜜儿
Because he wants a fogless shave mirror, honey.
不管了 最近过得怎样? 你家孩子们怎么样?
Anyway, how's everything else? How are your boys doing?
很好啊 埃迪和我发脾气 因为我不让他参加历史户外课
Fine. Eddie's mad at me because I won't let him go on his history field trip.
是去弗罗里达的殖民小镇吗?
The one to colonial floridatowne?
相信我 你做得太对了
Believe me, you're doing the right thing.
妮可儿去的时候我陪着去过了
I chaperoned when Nicole went,
我们就说说厕所这个最现实的问题吧
and let's just say the bathrooms are very realistic.
你刚才是说弗罗里达的殖民小镇吗?
Did you just say colonial floridatowne?
那些厕所其实就是些小木屋 然后在地上挖了洞而已
They are literally wood sheds with a hole in the ground.
我超爱美国殖民历史哒!
I love colonial american history!
美国的殖民者就像现在的中国人
Colonial americans were like the chinese of today.
他们的挣扎 他们的工作理念
Their struggle, their work ethic,
他们物尽其用的能力
Their ability to use every single part of the buffalo.
我的意思是 你看过我那些陶瓷殖民老鼠了吧
I mean, you've seen my porcelain colonial mice.
什么...?
What the...?
美国殖民者在最艰苦的环境里
Colonial americans survived
生存下来了
under the harshest of circumstances,
正因为此 他们值得我们尊敬
And for that, they deserve our respect.
看看这一个
Look at this one.
骄傲 勤劳
proud, hard-working,
把牛奶罐子伸向了这个世界
holding out her milk jug to the world
好像在说 "美国 尽管把你最糟糕的一面展示给我吧
as if to say, "Show me your worst, america.
我还是有牛奶可喝"
I'll still have milk."
这个看起来有点像莎莉·菲尔德(美国女演员)
This one looks a little bit like Sally Field,
你不觉得吗?
Don't you think?
我觉得她看起来是太像莎莉·菲尔德了
I think that one looks a lot like Sally Field.
你哥哥在哪儿呢?
Where's your brother?
他在房间里玩超级马里奥呢
He's playing super mario in his room.
他说用一个胜利来开始新的一天 感觉特别好
He says it's nice to start the day with a victory.
埃迪 你要迟到了!
Eddie, you're gonna be late!
不要再玩那两个意大利维修工兄弟了 赶快过来!
Stop playing italian maintenance twins and get in here!
回头 我要挖个垃圾焚烧坑 把这东西给烧了
Later, I'm going to dig a trash pit and burn this.
路易斯 你在干嘛啊? 穿上衬衫
Louis, what are you doing? Put a shirt on.
我觉得这个样子更舒服呢
I feel more comfortable this way.
你很讨厌不穿上衣啊
You hate being shirtless.
你在海里也会穿件T恤呢
You wear a t-shirt in the ocean.
我在努力向你展示
I'm trying to give you
你渴望的动作电影里的男性阳刚之气呢
the macho action-movie energy you clearly crave.
你在说啥啊?
What are you talking about?
我发现了 那些录影带 杰西卡
I found your tapes, jessica.
你藏在我们床垫子底下的那些
The ones you keep hidden under our mattress.
你的动作片带子
Your action-movie tapes.
我不看动作片的啊
I don't watch action movies.
我只看关于诉讼案情摘要的
The only movies I watch are riveting denzel dramas
丹泽尔剧集啊
about legal briefs.
"案情摘要在哪里?
"Where are the legal briefs?
谁有案情摘要?
Who has the legal briefs?
朱丽叶·罗伯茨 给我案情摘要"
Julia roberts, get me the legal briefs."
好吧 那如果不是你租的那些录影带 那是谁租的?
Okay, so if you didn't rent them, who did?
也许是你妈妈
Probably your mother.
我已经搜过她的房间了
I already searched her room.
只找到周润发的挂历
All I found was a Chow Yun-Fat calendar.
这个家里 有人对我撒谎
Somebody in this house is lying to me,
我会找出来是谁的
and I'm gonna find out who.
你忘了什么没有?
Forgetting something?
呃 为什么你要给我这个?
Uh, why are you giving me this?
我改主意了
I changed my mind.
你可以去参加历史户外课了
You can go on your history field trip.
真的吗?
Really?
妈妈 太感谢了
Thanks, mom.
等一下
Wait.
为什么你要戴帽子?
Why are you wearing a hat?
因为我要以监护人的身份 和你一起去
Because I'm coming with you as parent chaperone.
天一亮 我们就出发
We leave at first light.
啊哈!
Aha!
埃默里?
Emery?
听我解释
I can explain.
你生气了吗?
Are you mad?
额 没 没有 我没有生气啦
Oh, uh, no, no, I'm not, uh, mad.
我我我 只是 额
I-I-I-I-I-I'm just, um, well...
埃默里 你要知道 你现在处于一个 额 你的身体
You know, Emery, you're at an age where, uh, your body...
我说的身体是指...
A-a-and by that I mean...
额 父爱知道没有...
Uh, uh, uh, a father's love knows no...
格莱格•洛加尼斯是一个非常棒的... 还有百脑汇
Greg Louganis is a wonderful... and Broadway.
呃 虽然我们可能不是非常好的状态来...
Uh, although we may not live in the best state for...
那些带子 是学校做研究用的
The tapes were research for school.
我就知道
I knew it.
我就知道 这肯定和家庭作业有关
I knew it was homework-related.
也不全是 你知道我怎么总能轻易交到朋友吗?
Not exactly. You know how I've always made friends easily?
呃 现在学校里面 有点儿变了
Well, there's been a change at school.
好像是一夜之间变了的
It's like it happened overnight.
我要消耗5点法力值 召唤先祖之触
And I'm tapping five mana to cast ancestral tentacle grab,
造成2点群体伤害 对所有...
dealing two damage to all your...
你们都是笨蛋
you guys are dorks.
我要去扔瓶子 砸火车
I'm gonna go throw bottles at a train.
突然之间 我的所有朋友 都表现地像硬汉一样
Suddenly, all of my friends are acting like tough guys.
他们聊的都是 车啊 枪火啊
All they want to talk about is cars, fire,
还有用这个砸那个
and throwing things at other things.
这不是我的风格
And that's not me.
我都不知道该怎么和他们一起玩了
I don't even know how to hang with them anymore.
青春期来得又猛又快
Puberty strikes hard and quick,
就像看"辛德勒名单"到一半的时候 喝了一大杯汽水
like a large soda halfway through "Schindler's list."
不管怎样 这就是我租这些带子的原因
Anyway, that's why I rented the tapes.
录像店里有一整区都是关于硬汉的
The video store has a whole section on tough guys.
我还想说它们能帮我弄清楚呢
And I was hoping they might help me figure it out.
不过我现在知道该怎么做了
But I know what I'm gonna do.
我决定了 要写一首诗
I've decided to write a poem.
一首诗?
A poem?
给全班同学的
For class.
我要以诗的形式讲一个史诗般的故事
I'm gonna tell an epic story through verse
告诉他们大脑和肌肉一样重要
and show that brains are as valuable as brawn.
绝对不行
Big no to that.
幸好 作为一以服务客户为生的
Luckily, as a small-business owner
小企业家
who relies on customer service,
我知道怎么让别人喜欢和你交朋友
I understand the mechanics of getting people to like you.
你找到他们感兴趣的东西
You find out what makes them tick,
然后 通过这些东西 去了解他们
and then you use that to relate to them.
比如说 学校里的这些孩子们
Like, uh, these boys at school...
他们是怎么跟对方说话的?
how do they speak to each other?
他们大部分时间都在对骂
Well, they mostly just insult each other
还有讲"屁"的笑话
And make jokes about farts.
像 "谁放的屁?
Like, "Who farted?
你放的? 不，我放的
Did you fart? No, I farted.
屁 屁 屁"
Fart, fart, fart."
这笑话不错啊
That's a funny joke.
所以说 他们挺幽默的啊   很好
So, they have a sense of humor.   Good.
这就是赢得他们尊重的关键
That'll be the key to winning their respect.
欢迎来到
殖民区
佛罗里达小镇
第五组是黄 马斯特森
And group five is Huang, Masterson,
石头 塞尔比和皮尤
Stone, Selby, and Pew.
你们的监护人是黄女士
Your chaperone will be mrs. Huang.
鹅妈妈!
Mother goose!
等等 布莱恩 你姓皮尤?
Wait, Brian, your last name is Pew?
我们做朋友多久啦?
How long have we been friends?
太好了 我们都在一起
It's cool that we're all together.
好? 我妈妈是我们的监护人啊
Cool? My mom is our chaperone.
然后呢? 还是会很有趣的 对吧?
So? It'll still be fun, right?
想得美 我妈讨厌有趣的事
No way. My mom hates fun!
孩子们
Boys.
看吧
Here we go.
我们都还没进去 她就开始...
We're not even inside yet, and she's already starting...
- 我们要涂点口红 - 啥?!
- We're going rogue. - What?!
我看了地图 结果发现你们班
I looked at the map, and turns out your class is only hitting
只会去佛罗里达小镇的教育区
the educational parts of floridatowne,
这样我们就没时间看别的好东西了
which doesn't leave any time for the good stuff.
所以 我们要自己来
So we're going to forge our own way.
殖民者们也是这么干的
It's what the colonials would have done.
来吧!
Come on!
等什么呢 皮尤?
What are you waiting for, Pew?
跟上她
Follow her.
你忘记擦手了
You forgot to wipe.
嘿 查德
Hey, Chad.
想听个笑话吗?
Want to hear a joke?
你的脸看起来像个屁股
Your face looks like a butt,
你一开口 声音就像放屁
And whenever you talk, it sounds like a fart.
殖民区的女人就是这样
And that's how colonial women used milk
用牛奶 洗掉最顽固的污渍
to get out even the most stubborn of household stains.
现在 谁想来帮我洗掉这件汗衫的血迹呢?
Now, who wants to help me get the blood out of this undershirt?
快 快
Come on, come on!
* Some of the busiest rhymes ever made by man *
* Are goin' into this mike, written by this hand *
* Are comin' out of this mouth, made by this tongue, I'll tell you now my name *
* My name is Young, but so you think that it's your destiny *
* To get the best of me, but I suggest to be quiet, bro *
* Don't even try it from the east and west of me, takin' it *
* To never breakin' it to even shakin' it, groovin' it to always movin' it *
* 'Cuz I'm not fakin' it, pullin' out rhymes like books off the shelf *
* Born in England raised in Hollis, taught to go for myself *
* This is stone-cold rhymin', no frills, no fluffs *
* And it's no accident that these rhymes sound tough * All: Whoa!
* I'm goin' off, baby, there's no turnin' back *
* I'm on your TV, on your album, cassette, and 8-track *
* And when the show is finally finished, I'll be takin' my bow *
* My name is Young, and, yo, I got know-how *
哇 今天玩得好开心啊
Wow, that was fun.
谁会想到还可以以制作蜡烛为生啊
Who knew that making candles was a career possibility?
我放弃建筑业啦
Goodbye, architecture.
助产士的助手还亲了我呢
And I got a kiss from the midwife's assistant.
她没有亲你好吗
You didn't get a kiss from her.
她只是告诉了你 厕所在哪
You just asked her where the bathroom was.
我们之间产生了火花
We had a connection.
埃迪 你妈好好玩啊
Eddie, your mom is so fun.
跟她比起来 我妈真没意思
She makes my mom look straight-up garbage.
谁也不许和我妈说我说过
Nobody tell my mom I said that.
我只是一时头脑发热了才说的
I was just wrapped up in the moment.
对啊 埃迪
Yeah, eddie.
你妈要是没来的话 这次户外课 肯定糟透了
This field trip would've sucked without your mom.
我提议 我们一起凑钱
I vote we all pool our money
给她买点高档的巧克力
and buy her some fancy chocolates.
或者海盐什么的
sea salt or something.
好啊 好啊 好啊 好啊
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
你们说的对啊
Yeah, you guys are right.
嗨 妈 你今天好有趣啊
Hey, mom. You were fun today.
喔 谢谢 埃迪
Oh, thank you, eddie.
我很高兴你们玩得那么开心啊
I'm glad you and your friends had a good time.
你造吗 那个红头发的小孩
You know, that big red...
他在制皮革方面真的很有天赋啊
He has a real talent for tanning meat.
你没懂 我是说 你...今天很有趣
No, I mean, you were fun today.
你咋啦?
What is that all about?
你是在嫉妒你的朋友们和我玩得开心吗?
Are you jealous your friends had fun with your mom?
不是
No.
我是说 你 今天很有趣
You were fun today,
其实你是可以做一个有趣的妈妈的
which means you've always been capable of having fun.
你只是选择不做
You just chose not to.
当我想要养那只跑进奶奶房间的壁虎时
Where was fun mom when I wanted to keep that gecko
我那个有趣的妈妈怎么就不出现呢?
that got into grandma's room?
我把饮料洒在了机场电梯时 你也没觉得这好玩
Or when I spilled my slurpee on the moving walkway in the airport?
你本来可以一直很有趣的啊
You could've been fun this entire time.
喂?
Hello?
埃迪又打架了?
Eddie got into a fight?
埃迪打架了吗?
马德琳 我不是跟你说了要跟我报告所有事吗?
Madeline, what did I tell you about keeping me in the loop?
今天有两个孩子吐了 还有一个扭伤脚踝了
We had two vomits and a sprained ankle,
但没有人打架啊
But no fights today.
啥? 两个孩子吐了?
Really? Two vomits?
因为今天吃的是玉米卷嘛
It's taco day.
稍等麻袋
Wait.
埃迪没打架 那谁打架了...
If eddie didn't get into a fight, then who...
哎呀 不好
Oh, no.
我滴个天呐 出啥事儿啦?
Oh, my god. What happened?
你来的也太晚了吧 弄得我都错过了旋转跳跃健身课
You came so late that I missed a tony little gazelle masterclass
45大洋呢!
that I paid $45 for.
人们都说 "健身吧 人生就会美好的了"
You know that expression, "Oh, if you work out, everything else will"?
呵呵 都是套路
Well, that is not true.
噢 对了 埃默里打架了
Oh, and emery was in a fight.
那啥 这事儿其实没那么糟啦
You know, this isn't really as bad as it seems.
你就是被打了一拳嘛
So you got punched.
人们在一生中总是会被揍个一两次的
Everybody gets punched at some point in their lives.
你妈上周在酸奶店还不是被个女的打了一拳
Your mom got punched by a lady at the yogurt shop last week.
- 都怪你 - 怪我?
- This is all your fault. - My fault?
我没有按照我的方式去解决这件事
Instead of handling things my own way,
而是听取了你的建议 结果却是这个下场
I took your advice, and look what happened.
真是谢谢啊 爸爸
Thanks a lot, dad.
哟 埃文 告诉你个秘密
Yo, evan, want to hear a secret?
我知道你在我的毛巾上擦手了
If it's that you wipe your hands on my towel, I already know.
你咋知道的?
How do you know about that?
埃迪 我摸得出来毛巾湿不湿啊
I know what a damp towel feels like, eddie.
额
Whatever.
我是要跟你讲一个真的秘密啦
I'm trying to tell you a real secret.
妈妈其实很有趣
Mom is fun.
这并不是个秘密呀
That's not a secret.
我这些年一直在跟你说啊
I've been telling you that for years.
不是你的那种书呆子式的有趣
Not your nerd version of fun.
而是真正的有趣
Like actually fun.
今天我上户外课的时候 她...
Today at my field trip, she...
孩儿们! 你们是小镇餐馆的女服务生吗?
Boys! What are you, waitresses at a small-town diner?
就知道聊天
Stop chatting.
埃文 回房做作业去
Evan, finish your homework in your room.
埃迪 丢垃圾去
Eddie, take out the trash.
好的 母上大人
Okay, mommy.
行啊 你又变得不好玩了
Oh, cool, you're back to being zero fun.
真是醉了
Awesome.
可能我得再等个12年才能和有趣的妈妈玩吧
Maybe I'll experience fun mom again in another 12 years.
你以为我不想有趣吗?
You think I don't want to be fun mom?
我也很想做一个有趣的妈妈
I would love to be fun mom.
那就做啊
So then do it.
埃迪 我们今天玩得很开心
Eddie, we had fun today
那是因为我不用
because I didn't have to spend every minute
时时刻刻都要跟在你屁股后面唠叨你
chasing after you and nagging you.
有趣的妈妈会让你做作业吗?
You think fun mom could get you to do your homework
有趣的妈妈会给你打扫房间吗?
and clean your room?
不会的
No way.
这些事都是不好玩的妈妈做的
That's what this mom is for.
不好玩的妈妈才能做好这些事
This mom gets things done.
没做完作业不准喝果汁
No juice boxes until you finish your homework.
你的训诫就是对我最好的奖励
Your discipline is the only reward I need.
妈 我做对了 是吗?
Mom, I did the right thing, right?
这么对待埃默里
with emery.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
我没这么做啊
I don't do that.
加油 热火!
Go, you 'guanas!
加油 火箭!
Go, you barn owls!
为什么他们要叫女子篮球啊?
Why do they call it women's basketball?
这就是篮球嘛 对不对?
It's just basketball, am I right?
哦 天哪 你说得对
Oh, my god, you're right.
我不喜欢女子篮球
I hate women's basketball.
你真的觉得我改变自己
Do you really think I change who I am
来让别人喜欢我吗?
to get people to like me?
我现在知道电影和影片的区别在哪了
Now I understand the difference between a movie and a film.
眼睛好点儿了吗?
How's that eye?
还行
It's okay.
你别担心 我跟妈说
And don't worry. I told mom
我眼睛变这样 是因为我看望远镜太用力了
that I got it from looking too hard through my telescope.
我觉得她还挺为此自豪的?
I think she was proud?
那个 呃 我不该跟你说 你不能表现自己的样子
I, uh, shouldn't have told you to act like somebody you're not.
你就是你 你不需要为真正的自己而感到任何羞愧
You're your own person, you're not ashamed of it,
而且这也是你的优点
and that's your strength.
这话你该跟我那些同学说说
Tell that to the boys at my school.
他们只是忙着
They're just too busy
去搞清楚他们到底是什么样的人
trying to figure out who they are to notice.
你也许觉得你现在跟不上他们的队伍
You may feel like you're falling behind the curve right now,
但是相信我 你领先了他们很多
But trust me, you are way ahead of it.
谢谢你 老爸
Thanks, dad.
- 你知道吗 也许我只需要改变一下我的策略 - 很好
- You know, maybe I just need to change my tactics. - Good.
- 然后以完全不同的方式 把我的诗传达给别人 - 噢
- And deliver my poem in a completely different way. - Oh.
我要证明给查德 还有其他男生看
I need to show Chad and those other boys
人生的战斗中 不是只能用你的拳头
that you don't need to fight all your battles with your fists.
有时候 你也可以用诗歌韵律来说话
Sometimes you can use the power of rhymed verse.
好的
Okay.
反正你自己看着办 好吗?
Just be smart about it, all right?
不用担心 老爸
Don't worry, dad.
这就是我
That's who I am.
你们俩要错过地精的葬礼了!
You guys are missing the gnome's funeral!
我想知道这个片子有没有第二部啊
I wonder if there's a "La chouffe 2."
埃迪 马上起床 去上学
Eddie, up now. School.
我听了你昨天说的 我也懂了
I heard what you said yesterday, and I get it.
有时候 我可能太过了
Sometimes, I can be a little much.
只是有时候?
Sometimes?
其实... 闭嘴
More like... not now.
好的 妈妈
Yes, mommy.
现在我理解了 为什么我在这儿能开心
I understand now that the only reason
唯一的理由是
why I have any fun around here
你过得不开心
is because you're not having any,
而这完全不公平啊
and that's not fair.
所以我今早 早早就准备好了
That's why I got myself ready this morning.
我甚至还打包好了午餐... 六个奥利奥还有一个玉米饼
I even packed my own lunch... six oreos and a tortilla.
谢谢你 埃迪
Thank you, eddie.
虽然我知道你昨天没洗澡
Even though I can tell you didn't shower
因为你闻起来一股子香肠披萨饼味儿
because you smell like a pepperoni pizza,
我还是为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you.
但是这意味着 我们现在多出了30分钟
But that means we're 30 minutes ahead of schedule.
我到底是这个绿门卫还是红门卫?
Am I the green janitor or the red janitor?
都不是 妈 你5分钟之前就挂了
Neither, mom. You died five minutes ago.
你只是傻不拉叽还在那儿敲键盘
You've just been pressing buttons for no reason.
"除了花与树 不知为谁
"And for who but the flowers and the trees
男人说着也唱着他的奇怪念想"
Doth man speak and sing his many whimsies."
写诗这种事 是娘炮才干的
Poetry's for 'ginas.
"而就算是拳头 也会被粉碎或扭伤"
"And though a fist may crush and sprain,
而大脑却是最强的武器"
There is no weapon like the brain."
这首诗 明显是一个思想敏锐的学生写的
This poem was written by a clearly sensitive student.
那就是我们的查德
Our very own chad.
非常棒 查德
Lovely work, chad.
不不不
No.
这不是我写的 我发誓!
That wasn't me, I swear!
没必要这么害羞 查德
No need to be bashful, chad.
这首诗写的很好
It was a beautiful poem.
我非常喜欢这首诗
I really like that poem.
我也是
Me, too.
这韵律里藏了很强大的力量
There's real power in rhymed verse.
哦 天 我的笔掉了
Oops. I dropped my pencil.
我们一起去喷乌龟吧
let's go spray-paint some turtles.
哦 嘿 路易斯
Oh, hey, louis.
我们刚来了一部超棒的丹麦电影
We just got an amazing danish film
"珂赛特和温柔小丑"
"Cosette and the gentle clown."
说的是一个叫珂赛特的年轻女孩的故事
It tells the story of a young girl, Cosette,
她离开了那座压迫的小矿村 去拜师...
who leaves her oppressive mining village to apprentice...
我要租"贝多芬"
I'm renting "Beethoven."
我觉得你是不是要租"莫扎特传"
I think maybe you meant to get "Amadeus."
那个在...
That's over in...
不是
No, I didn't.
我才不想看"莫扎特传"
I don't want to watch "Amadeus."
"莫扎特传"看起来很无聊
"Amadeus" looks boring.
就跟你推荐的所有电影一样无聊
Just like all the movies you recommend.
从现在开始 我只租
From now on, I'm only renting
我喜欢的电影
the kind of movies that I like.
关于动物的电影... 动作的... 疯狂的
Movies about animals... Acting...Crazy.
随便你咯 老兄
Whatever, man.
太棒了!
Yeah!